

Matteo Ciniselli

Personal Information

Lugano, Switzerland

Italian (B permit)

🛗 29 August 1990

+41798482662

⊠ ilcini90@gmail.com

https://mciniselli.github.io

Programming Languages

Python $\star\star\star\star\star$ SQL $\star\star\star\star\star$ Machine/Deep Learning $\star\star\star\star\star$ NLP $\star\star\star\star\star$ Git/Docker $\star\star\star\star\star$ R Studio $\star\star\star\star\star$ AWS $\star\star\star\star\star$

Languages

Italian, Mother Tongue English, Highly Fluent German, Beginner

Passions

Artificial Intelligence Traveling

Summary

I'm an experienced Data Scientist with a strong passion for AI and programming.

I have pursued the Ph.D. in Computer Science from the Faculty of Informatics at the Università Della Svizzera Italiana (USI) in Lugano where I'm currently working as a Data Scientist.

These experiences have allowed me to develop excellent problem-solving skills, strong interpersonal and communication skills essential for effective teamwork, and proficient time management abilities.

Work Experience

Data Scientist

Università della Svizzera Italiana

Jan 2024 – Today

- Actively participated in Machine Learning projects, presenting my results at international events.
- Effectively leaded a team of three people overseeing their activities to ensure the successful and timely completion of ongoing projects.

Data Scientist @ Machine Learning Center of Excellence**Accenture** **Mar 2019 - Apr 2020**

- Developed Front-End applications with Flask, HTML, and Bootstrap to deploy Machine Learning services and Computer Vision projects.
- Orchestrated the deployment of Docker containers exposing a Node.js server, integrating AI into home appliances and enabling the vocal interaction between users and a washing machine.

.NET Developer Aglea

Oct 2017 - Feb 2019

- Implemented a comprehensive tool for managing company activities such as purchasing, invoicing, and device management, using a SQL database and DevExpress framework.
- Gained foundational knowledge in SAP ERP fundamentals.

Data Analyst/Scientist NextInt

Jan 2015 – Sep 2017

- Developed Dashboards and Reports using QlikView.
- Implemented Machine and Deep Learning projects using Python, Rapidminer, and R Studio, to help customers leverage their corporate data for informed decision-making.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Università della Svizzera Italiana

May 2020 - Dec 2023

My Ph.D. research is centered on leveraging Machine and Deep Learning models to facilitate the automatic generation of text. Throughout my research papers, I conducted Generative AI experiments with various cutting-edge models such as T5, CodeT5, RoBERTa, and GitHub Copilot.

Master in High Apprenticeship in Analytics and Business Intelligence Polytechnic of Milan Jul 2015 – Jul 2017

During my Master's, I extensively delved into Big Data and Machine Learning topics. Additionally, I developed a tool utilizing NoSQL databases (MongoDB) and a NodeJS architecture integrated with Angular to solve Machine Learning tasks.

Bachelor's and Master's Degree in Mathematical Engineering (Statistics)

Polytechnic of Milan

Sep 2009 – Apr 2015

I comprehensively explored Machine Learning and Statistics, augmenting my expertise through Data Analysis, Probability, and Programming courses.